# ANDRÉS ALEXANDRO TAPIA

#### SUMMARY

Full stack software developer from Ecuador and mechatronics engineer with experience in **languages** and frameworks like: JavaScript (React - NextJs, AngularJs, Angular, Express), Python (Flask, Django, Jinja), CSS (Bootstrap, Sass), C++, C#, Java, HTML, VBScript, MQL4 – MQL5, Ladder, LabVIEW, MATLAB. And designing and managing databases in MongoDB, Redis, MySQL, Firebase, and others. **Experience using and developing in Microsoft Azure, AWS, Google and other paid and Open-Source technologies** (Git, Postman, Celery, RabbitMQ, Netlify, Vercel, Twilio, DialogFlow, Jira, Slack, HubSpot, Zapier, Hubstaff, Bitbucket).

Current and previous personal projects: <a href="https://kingsofbinary.com">https://devlocalhost.com</a>, <a href="https://kingsofbinary.com">https://devlocalhost.com</a>, <a href="https://alexandrotapia.vercel.app">https://alexandrotapia.vercel.app</a>, co-author of a paper "Pose Estimation Based on Monocular Visual Odometry and Lane Detection for Intelligent Vehicles". <a href="https://scihub.tw/10.1007/978-3-319-95282-6">https://scihub.tw/10.1007/978-3-319-95282-6</a> 40.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **ESPE (Escuela Superior Politécnica del Ejército)**

Mechatronics Engineer (Best graduate)

July - 2019

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS AND LANGUAGES

- Programming languages: Javascript,
  Python, HTML, CSS, C#, C++, VBScript,
  Ladder (PLC), MQL4, MQL5, Java, MATLAB.
- Databases: MongoDB, Redis, MySQL,
  Firebase Firestore, Firebase Real time database.
- Frameworks: Django, Flask, Express.
  NextJs, Angular, AngularJs
- DevOps: Linode, DigitalOcean, Nginx, Certbot, PM2, Docker, Terraform, Ionos, Freenom, Hostinger, Vagrant, Git, Github, Bitbucket.
- Other software used: Slack, Jira, HubSpot, Zapier, Hubstaff, Twilio.
- Spanish: Native, English: Fluent, German: Medium.
- Other skills: AutoCAD, SOLIDWORKS, Photoshop, Video Editing.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Ten Tech Feb 2014 - Jul 2018

Software developer, specialist in mechatronics.

- Ladder
- C++
- Java
- Python
- MATLAB
- WordPress
- React (Class based components)
- Data Science
- Git
- Github

ESPE Sep 2018 – Dic 2018

Leader software developer of a team focused on the rehabilitation of kids with autism (Social robots).

- LabVIEW
- C++
- C#
- VBScript

### **Localhost (entrepreneurship)**

Feb 2019 - Current

Jan 2020 - Current

CEO and developer of the company.

- Atlassian products (Jira, Confluence, Bitbucket)
  - Leadership
  - Figma
  - Illustrator
  - CI/CD
  - Terraform
- Software Architecture

# Kings Of Binary

Co-founder, software architect and TechLead.

- Node.js
- Next.js
- Flask
- Firebase
- Linode
- Nginx
- Certbot
- Wordpress
- Terraform
- MQL4 MQL5
- Blockchain
- Solidity

Devsu Oct 2020 - Current

Sr. Full stack developer, specialist in Python and Node.js.

- AngularJS
- Angular
- Django
- Docker
- Celery
- RabbitMQ
- AWS (IAM, EC2, ROUTE53, S3, RDS, SQS, SES)
  Firebase (auth, real-time database, firestore, firebase hosting)
- Data Studio
- Twilio and products (close contact with the company, projects and feature requests)

## **Freelancing - Other companies**

Apr 2017 - Current

Backend developer, Software Architect.

- SCRUM, Kanban
- Perl
- Nginx
- AWS
- Solidity
- \_